上帝会对那些站在左边的人说
Then God will say to those on the left:
远离我 你们永远都会被诅咒
"Depart from me, ye cursed,
那是为恶魔和他的使徒准备的
into everlasting life that was prepared for the devil and his angels.
当我饥饿的时候 你什么都没有给我吃
For I was hungry and you gave me nothing to eat.
当我渴的时候 你什么都没有给我喝
I was thirsty and you gave me nothing to drink.
我对于是一个陌生人 你不会带上我
I was a stranger and you did not take me in.
当我赤裸的时候 你没有给我衣服穿
I was naked and you did not clothe me.
当我生病的时候 你没有照顾我
I was sick and you did not tend me.
当我在监狱的时候 你没有来看望我
I was in prison and you did not visit me."
然后他们会说 主啊
And they will say, "Lord,
我们什么时候没能做到这些事呢
when did we fail to do these things?"
于是主会回答道
And the Lord will reply:
哪怕是最小的一件事情
"Whatever you failed to do for the least of men
只要你没有为我做 就算你没做到
you failed to do for me."
这些人会被卷入永不熄灭的火中受难
And they will go away to everlasting fire
而正义则会永久长存
while the righteous will have eternal life.
谢谢你 莱特斯
Thank you, Letters.
他们是在我们抛尸的那个位置吗
Are they where we dumped the body?
当时天色很暗
It was dark.
全能的上帝啊
God Almighty.
我能告诉你们我为什么爱这个地方吗
Shall I tell you what I love about this place?
他们看到马斯顿了
They have seen Marston!
可以吗
Shall I?
他们在那里什么也看不到
There is nothing to see.
谁愿意帮我建一座教堂呢 谁
Who will help me build a church, who?
莱特斯·莫洛伊愿意 上帝
Letters Molloy, Lord!
Letters Molloy, Lord.
你最渴望的是什么呢 莱特斯
And the thing which you most desire, Letters?
在我死前能再看一眼塔沙湖
To see Dri-shane Lake once more before I die.
你会的 因为上帝会满足你最大的愿望
And you shall! Because god will grant your dearest wish.
他能清楚地听到你的声音
He will hear you loud and clear.
我们完了
We are finished.
还有谁 还有人原意帮我建造教堂吗
Who else, who else will help me build a church?
是我们完了
We?
威廉·斯塔宾斯愿意 上帝
William Stubbins, Lord.
只有我
I am.
威廉·斯塔宾斯愿意 上帝
William Stubbins, Lord!
我完了
I am finished.
“我就是复活 就是生命”
I am the resurrection and the light.
“信我的人 虽然死了 也必复活”
He who believes in me even though he dies shall live.
“凡活着信我的人 必永远不死”
Whoever lives and believes in me shall never die.
听不到你们说什么
Cannot hear you!
尘归尘 土归土
Ashes to ashes, dust to dust.
要相信这些知识是关于
Be sure of certain knowledge of the ...
我们听不到
We cannot hear you!!
他在喊他们过去
He’s telling them to come ... amen.
阿门
Amen.
把罗斯少校找来
Get Major Ross!
下士 我说去把罗斯上校叫来
Corporal, I said get me Major Ross.
马上
Now!
罗斯上校来了 长官
Major Ross, sir!
放肩膀上
Shoulder
向前 手臂
Advance,Arm
再让我看到这个 我会指控你
If I see that again you’ll be on a charge
明白了吗
do you understand?
抱歉中士
Sorry sarge?
让蒂明斯过来
Fetch Timmins.
是的长官
Sir.
放肩膀上
Shoulder.
长官
Sir.
你找到她了
You found her then?
是的 长官
Yes, Sir
你昨天在哪
Where were you yesterday?
四处走了走 长官
Here and there, Boss.
我找了你一整天
I was looking for you all day.
对不起 长官
I am sorry, Boss.
我派了土兵去找你
I sent soldiers to look for you.
是吗 长官
Did you, Boss?
我还跟犯人们说了我在找你
I told convicts I was looking for you.
如果他们见到你了 就告诉你
And if they saw you, they were to tell you that.
没人告诉过我 长官
Nobody did, Boss.
蒂明斯中士来了 长官
Sergeant Timmins.Sir
进来
Come!
长官
Sir
我是有自尊的 凯瑟琳·麦克维蒂
I have pride, Katherine Mcvitie. .
你得尊重我
I demand respect
出去
Go.
在蒂明斯中士的帮助下
And with the help of Sergeant Timmins here
我是一名士兵 女人
I am a soldier, woman.
长官的一切命令 士兵都会照做
A soldier does what his commanding officer tells him to do
出去
Go!
是的 长官
Going, Sir!
在蒂明斯中士的帮助下
With the help of Sergeant Timmins here,
我会让你尊重我的
I will get your respect.
蒂明斯中士
Sergeant Timmins.
长官
Sir
你排在名单上第几位
What number were you on the list?
十九 长官
Nineteen, Sir.
你是第19个选女人的
You had nineteenth choice of a woman?
是的 长官
Yes, Sir.
你选了谁
Whom did you choose?
莎拉·帕金森 长官
Sarah Parkinson, Sir.
你为什么选萨拉·帕金森
Why did you prefer Sarah Parkinson,
那个丑陋又满嘴脏话的老巫婆
an ugly, foul - mouthed hag,
而不选凯瑟琳·麦克维蒂呢
to Katherine Mcvitie here?
我没有看到凯瑟琳·麦克维蒂 长官
I did not see Katherine Mcvitie, Sir.
你愿意在军事法庭上宣誓作证吗
Would you swear to that at court martial?
如果必须的话 长官
If I had to, Sir.
但如果是她把自己藏了起来
But it would suggest she hid herself away
仅当轮到他心上人做选择时才出现
to reappear only when it was her lover's turn to choose.
她的爱人会因此被枪毙的
It would get her lover shot?
是的 长官
Yes, Sir.
我们该逮捕他吗 凯瑟琳
Shall we arrest him, Katherine?
麦克唐纳下士来了 长官
Corporal Macdonald, Sir!
长官
Sir.
什么事
Yes?
柯林斯上尉找您 长官
Captain Collins needs you, Sir.
嗯
Oh.
凯瑟琳
Katherine?
我今晚会去你那里的 长官
I will come to you tonight, boss.
谢谢
Thank you.
别带着一张抑郁的脸来
Do not come sullen.
我希望看到你脸上的微笑
I will expect to see a smile up upon your face.
中士
Sergeant.
长官
Sir
走吧
Come on.
下士
Corporal.
我只剩下大概一个小时可以活了
I only have an hour or so left to live
我要尽情享受这一个小时
and I am going to enjoy it.
对不起 你不用害怕
I am sorry. Please do not be frightened.
你来这里干什么
What are you doing here?
他的朗姆酒放在哪儿
Where does he keep his rum?
是他让你来拿的吗
Has he sent you for it?
算是吧 在哪呢
In a way. Where is it?
那边
Over there.
这酒是给谁的
Who is that for?
我
Er, me.
你打算偷喝总督的朗姆酒吗
You intend to drink the Governor's rum?
对
Yes
他会因此而把你绞死的
He will hang you for it.
他们说的那些是真的吗
Is it true what they say?
他们说什么了
What do they say?
你和总督在一起了
You and the Governor.
谁说的
Who says it?
所有人
Everybody.
所有人吗
Everybody?
对
Yes
他们都说他把你的丈夫派到了开普敦
They all say that he sent your husband to Cape Town
这样你和他就
so that you and he ...
不 不是真的
No, it is not true.
那你希望是这样吗
Would you like it to be?
请你离开
Please go.
我保证把酒杯给你送回来
I will make sure you get this back.
很抱歉让你受惊了
I am sorry for startling you.
他们找到了什么东西
They have found something.
尸体吗
The body?
有可能
Perhaps.
总督的酒
The Governor's.
你偷了总督的朗姆酒
You stole the Governor's rum?
他还能把我绞死两次吗
Can he hang me twice?
柯林斯上尉
Captain Collins.
早安 长官
Good morning sir!
我们的渔网 长官 已经被撕成碎片了
Our nets, Sir. They have been ripped to shreds.
被鲨鱼吗
Sharks?
当地人
Natives.
他们肯定认为我们抢了他们太多的鱼
They must think we take too much fish with them.
太好了
Yes
太多吗 我们基本捕不到东西
Too much? We hardly catch anything.
尽管这样
Nevertheless.
该死的
Shit!
糟糕
Oh no!
之前那么神气
So cocky before.
现在却又这么胆小
So timid now.
我之前以为我走投无路了
I thought I had nothing to lose
但其实没有
but I have.
求你别告诉总督 别绞死我
Please do not tell the Governor. Please do not hang me.
你做了什么被送到这儿来
What did you do to end up here?
这会影响你的决定吗
Will that affect your decision?
是的
Yes
那样的话
In that case .
我死定了
I am doomed.
我只是
I, am ...
一个扒手
a pickpocket
如果我同意帮你
If I agree,
你会帮我做点事作为回报吗
will you do something for me in return?
是的
Yes
不管什么时候
Whenever
只要你听到有人议论我和总督的事
you hear anyone talk about me and the Governor,
你会对他们澄清一下吗
will you put them straight?
我会的
Yes
总督并没有把我的丈夫派到开普敦
The Governor did not send my husband to Cape Town.
他是自愿去的
He volunteered
我也永远不会背叛他
and I would never betray him.
我会跟他们澄清事实的 我保证
I will put them straight, I promise.
很好
Very well.
我同意不告诉总督了
I agree not to tell the Governor.
弗里曼
Freeman!
他在哪
Where is he?
事情已经解决了
It is taken care of.
你们又把马斯顿挖出来了吗
You dug up Marston again?
跟你没关系
That is none of your concern.
我们都是在一条船上的
We are in this together.
你把他挖出来了吗
Have you dug him up?
只能这样 不然狗也会把他挖出来的
We had to or the dogs would have done it for us.
我们没法把他埋得很深
We could not dig him in deep.
他现在在哪
Where is he now?
海底 被他自己做的锁链沉下去了
The bottom of the sea. Weighed down with his own chains.
我们
We er,
我们发誓会保持沉默
we all swore an oath of silence.
这有必要吗
Was that necessary?
你会告发我们吗
Would you grass on us?
不会
No
矮子呢
Stubby?
不会
No
莱特斯呢
Letters?
不会
No
谁会 谁会
Anyone? Anyone?
不会 不会
No.No
没有人 既然我这么信任你们
So why the oath
还有必要发誓吗
if I am already sure of you?
矮子
Stubby.
我们想让你和总督谈谈
We want you to speak to the Governor.
谈什么
What about?
削减配给粮的事
This cut in the rations.
以此报答你们的沉默吗
In return for your silence?
我们的沉默是无偿的 伊丽莎白
Our silence is a given, Elizabeth.
你去向总督抗议 你是一个被定性的人
You complain to the Governor, you are a marked man.
他已经给你贴了标签了
He has already marked you:
一个愿意为原则而死的男人
a man ready to die for a principle.
他尊重你
He has respect for you.
你是唯一能告诉他的人
You are the only one that can tell him.
你知道他会说什么吗
You know what he will say?
“你太把自己当回事了 巴伦特
"Getting above yourself Barrett.
虽然我之前没有绞死你
Because I did not hang you,
但现在我会
so now I will,
你这个口无遮拦 傲慢自大
you big-mouthed, big-headed,
蛊惑人心的白痴”
rabble rousing fool."
不 不 不 他会为此感激你的
No, no, no. He will thank you for it.
你得告诉他这次减少配给
You tell him that this cut in the rations
会将他和所有的士兵置于危险之中
endangers him and all the soldiers.
为什么这么说
How?
我们被统治是因为我们接受统治
We are governed because we allow ourselves to be governed.
我们有一千人 他们只有区区一百人
A thousand of us and a hundred of them?
如果我们想造反他们一点办法都没有
They won’t stand a chance if we chose to rebel.
他会把这话当成是威胁
He will see that as a threat.
他会把这当成一个
He will see it as a word
来自他所尊敬的人的提醒
of warning from a man that he respects
你这样想吗
You think so?
是的 我这样想
Yes I do.
那你去告诉他
Then you tell him.
您要见我吗 教士
You want me, Reverend?
是的
Yes
如果我妻子来了
If my wife comes,
你就说你是来取要洗的衣服的 好吗
you are here to take her laundry. Yes?
好的
Yes
你是怎么知道我们孩子的事情的
How did you find out about our babies?
你是怎么知道的
How did you find out?
我从她眼中看出来的
I read it in her eyes.
安妮
Anne,
这里的人
people here
是淳朴的
are unsophisticated.
你说这种话
Talk like that
他们会把你吊在火刑柱上烧死 明白吗
can get you burnt at the stake, do you understand?
最好不要再让我听到这种话
Best not to hear it anymore.
是
Yes
还有 请离我妻子远一点 安妮
And stay away from my wife please, Anne.
可以做到吗
Will you do that?
可以
Yes
很好
不要对任何人说这件事
Good. Not a word to anyone about this.
当然
Of course.
很好
Good
主啊 我们祈求您保佑
Oh lord, we ask you, to bless all .
所有为这座教堂劳作的人
who labour on this church.
.
祈愿能有一个美好的结局
May the end result be a thing of beauty.
我们同样祈求您 主啊
We ask you also Lord, to bless the marriage .
请祝福伊丽莎白·奎恩
... of Elizabeth Quinn
和托马斯·布伦特的婚姻
and Thomas Barrett.
愿您仁慈地看待他们的结合
May you look kindly upon the circumstances of their union ...
打扰一下
Excuse me.
这里在干什么
What is going on here?
我们在祝福 伊丽莎白·奎恩
We are blessing the marriage of Elizabeth Quinn
和托马斯·布伦特的婚姻
and Thomas Barrett.
我是说 这是谁做的
I mean this. Who has done this?
所有这些人
These men.
用他们的空闲时间吗
In their own time?
在这个炎热的下午吗
In the heat of the afternoon?
是的
Yes.
我们 我们努力在晚上之前
We, we are attempting to raise the crucifix
竖起十字架
by the end of the afternoon.
今天是你们休息的日子
Today is your day of rest!
这个仪式结束后
When this service is over
你们要找到躲避烈日的地方
you will find some shelter from the sun
你们需要休息
and you will rest.
今天你们不准再干活了
You must do no more work today.
是 长官
Yes Boss.
你不舒服吗
Is there something the matter?
没有 没有 长官
No, no Boss.
谢谢
Thank you.
你今晚能来见我吗
Will you come and see me tonight please?
当然 我们做错了什么吗
Of course. Have we done something wrong?
我们晚上再说
We will talk tonight.
敬爱的主啊
Dear lord,
愿您仁慈地看待他们的结合
may you look kindly upon the circumstances of their union.
怎么了
What is it?
你不舒服吗 伊丽莎白
Are you unwell, Elizabeth?
我很好 很好 请继续
I am fine, fine. Please, please continue.
他们因为彼此相爱而结合
A union brought about by their great love for each other,
为了证明这一点
as demonstrated
托马斯·巴雷特宁愿牺牲自己的
by Thomas Barrett's willingness to forsake his own ...
嗨 嗨 嗨 怎么了
Hey, hey, hey. What is it?
我想我怀孕了
I think I am pregnant.
我要当父亲了
I am to be a father!!!
我要有孩子了
The boy’s still got it!
This boy still got it.
太棒了
Yes!
这位是威廉·斯塔宾斯 总督
This is William Stubbins, Governor.
你好
How do you do?
你好 总督
How do you do, Governor?
他认为他可以帮我们
He thinks he can help us.
是吗
Yes?
我会一点锻造 总督
I know my way around the forge, Governor.
我当过一年的学徒
I did one year as an apprentice.
我本来会继续干下去 但后来进了监狱
I would have done it all but I went to prison.
你会打造什么
Can you make anything?
钉子
Nails.
钉子吗
是的 总督
Yes, Governor.
别的呢 锤子 或者
Nothing else? Hammers or...?
不能 总督 但是我会修理
No, Governor. But I can repair things.
我会练习 练习 再练习
I will practise, practise, practise.
再过上一两年
In a year or two
我一定能做出任何你想要的东西
I will be able to make anything you need.
在那之前 我会修好所有坏了的东西
Till then I will fix everything that gets broken.
很好 给自己招个学徒
Good. Find yourself an apprentice
好好教他
and show him everything.
是的 总督
Yes, Governor.
我可以要求一点回报吗
May I ask for something in return?
可以
Yes
我有个妻子 在我的家乡
I have a wife back home.
对我来说 她意味着全世界
And she means the world to me.
她写信说她会等着我
She has written here that she will wait for me.
但是我要服刑十四年 总督
But I am doing fourteen years, Governor.
我不能让她等我长达十四年
And I cannot ask her to wait for fourteen years.
努力工作 好好为我们服务
Work hard, serve us well
四五年以后 你们就能团聚了
and you will be together in four or five.
你可以走了
You may go.
谢谢您
Thank you
我们有铁匠了
We have a blacksmith!!!
太好了 太好了
Yes!Yes!
恭喜你
Congratulations.
怎么了
What’s wrong?
不让我们干了
We have been told to stop.
谁不让了
By whom?
总督
The Governor.
但它已经起作用了
But it works.
上帝听见了我们的声音
God hears us!
上尉
Captain.
我能为你做点什么吗 少校
Can I help you with something, Major?
凯瑟琳·麦克维蒂说她是无辜的
Katherine Mcvitie says she’s innocent.
是吗
Really?
她说当时她正在打理那位勋爵的卧室
She told me she was working in his lordship's bedroom
勋爵走了进来 企图强暴她
when he entered and forced himself upon her.
是吗
Yes?
她可能讲的是实情
She could be telling the truth?
恐怕这不是事实 少校 不是
I am afraid not, Major, no.
不是吗
No?
她是楼下的女仆 罗斯少校
She was the downstairs maid, Major Ross.
她根本不该靠近那位勋爵的卧室
She should not have been anywhere near his lordship's bedroom.
噢 我明白了
Ah. I see.
抱歉
I am sorry.
没必要道歉 她只是个妓女而已
There’s no need to apologise. She is only a whore..
晚安
Good night
你怎么知道那些的
How do you know that?
她档案里都写着呢
It is in her file.
你有上千个档案 你看过所有的内容吗
You have a thousand files. Would you know what is in them all?
没有
No
那你怎么知道凯瑟琳·麦克维蒂的事呢
Then why Katherine Mcvitie's?
因为她太漂亮了 罗斯少校
Because she is so beautiful, Major Ross.
而且我听说你跟她走得很近
And I heard you were getting ... rather close.
好吧 谢谢你
Ah, well, thank you.
谢谢你
Thank you
你想做什么
What do you want?
这可能是我的
It could be mine.
你指什么
What could?
你的孩子
Your baby.
你的孩子可能是我的
Your baby could be mine.
我可不信
I doubt it.
他需要一个真正的父亲 而不是虚构的
It needs a man, not a shirt button.
我该告诉他吗
Should I tell him?
告诉汤米吗
Tommy?
是的
Yeah
那可不是一个好主意
That would not be a good idea.
我该保密吗
I should stay silent?
是的
Yes
回报呢
And in return?
你有什么建议吗
What do you suggest?
我想再
I want you.
要你一次
Again.
这里的男人是女人的五倍多
Five men to every woman:
为了得到女人 男人就得不择手段
a man must do whatever it takes.
你很享受这个 是吗
And you would enjoy that, would you?
是的
Yes
享受和一个鄙视你的女人做爱吗
Shagging a woman who you know despises you.
没错
Yes
你会从中得到快乐吗
You would get pleasure from such a thing?
反正这里所有人都瞧不起我
It seems there is no one here that does not despise me.
所以 没错 我就是能从中得到快乐
So yes, I would get pleasure from it.
那么 我们去找汤米谈谈
Let us talk to Tommy then.
什么
what?
你可以把一切都告诉汤米
You can tell all this to Tommy.
你在开玩笑
You are joking.
我没有
I am not.
你在吓唬我
You are bluffing.
我没有
I am not.
他会杀了你
He would kill you.
有可能
He might.
但他绝对会杀了你
He would definitely kill you.
巴克利列兵
Private Buckley!
是的 长官
Yes sir.
你没有行礼
You did not salute.
对不起 长官
I am sorry, Sir.
有什么问题吗
What is wrong?
没有 长官
Nothing, Sir.
把凯瑟琳·麦克维蒂给我带过来
Bring Katherine Mcvitie to me.
遵命 长官
Yes, Sir.
如果她不从 就拽过来
Drag her if you must.
遵命 长官
Sir.
我们可以一起逃走
We could run away together.
去哪
To where?
去丛林里
The Bush.
我们会死在那的
We would die there.
杰弗森就没死
Jefferson did not die.
你怎么知道
How do you know?
他没有回来
He has not returned.
杰弗森没回来
Jefferson did not return
是因为他已经死在丛林了
because he died in the Bush.
或者 他没回来是因为他做对了
Or he has not returned because he was right:
你能在丛林里活下来
you can live in the Bush.
凯瑟琳·麦克维蒂 请吧
Katherine Mcvitie please!
我们现在就可以走
We could go now.
趁天黑吗
In darkness?
是的
Yes
我看到只老鼠都会尖叫 看到蟑螂也会
I scream at the sight of a mere mouse. A cockroach even.
我怎么能够在丛林里适应这些呢
How would I cope with the things that live in the Bush?
我会照顾你的 我发誓我会
I will look after you, I promise I will ...
凯瑟琳·麦克维蒂 该跟我走了
Katherine Mcvitie, you are to come with me
我们在讲话
We are talking!
我奉命立刻护送你
... right now, please. Because I have orders to escort you
到罗斯少校那里去
to Major Ross immediately
我们在讲话
We are talking!
如果你现在不跟我走
so if you do not come with me right now
我就会把你拽去他那
I will drag you to him
我们在讲话 伙计
We are talking, man!
我的命令中包括
Because my orders include
在不得已的时候有权使用武力
The right to use force if I have to!!
巴克利列兵
Private Buckley!
他被迫和别人分享他的女人
He has to share his woman.
但至少他还有个女人
But at least he has one to share.
你不能 永远不能 罗斯少校的皮条客
You do not.You never will, Major Ross' pimp,
因为你是个非常丑陋的人
because you are a very ugly man.
你是什么
What are you?
一个非常丑陋的人 中士
A very ugly man, Sarge.
从内到外
Inside and out.
现在就回到罗斯少校那去
Now go back to Major Ross
然后告诉他凯瑟琳·麦克维蒂
and tell him that Katherine Mcvitie
会在半小时内过去
will be with him in half an hour.
告诉他 是蒂明斯中士保证的
Tell him that Sergeant Timmins has given his word on that.
遵命 中士
Sarge.
快去
Go
遵命
Sarge.
半小时
Half an hour.
是的 长官
Sir
脱下你的肩章
Take off your stripes!
解开你的腰带
Take off your sash.
我受够了被当作狗屎一样对待
I am sick of being treated like shit!
解开你的腰带和我打一架 一对一
Take off your sash and fight me man to man.
不
No
脱下你的腰带和我打一架 你这个懦夫
Take off your sash and fight me, you bloody coward.
好吧
Right.
开始吧
Proceed.
够了吗
Enough?
还是我 巴克利列兵 长官
Private Buckley again, Sir.
长官 蒂明斯中士说凯瑟琳·麦克维蒂
Sir. Sergeant Timmins says Katherine Mcvitie
会在半小时内过来 长官 他做了保证
will be here in half an hour, Sir, he gives his word on that.
你的脸怎么了
What happened to your face?
我摔倒了 长官
I fell over, Sir.
我可以走了吗 长官
May I go, Sir?
你哭了吗
Are you crying?
没有 长官
No, Sir.
眼泪 长官 是的 长官 但是
Tears, Sir, yes but ...
是因为愤怒 长官 不是哭泣 长官
tears of anger, Sir. Not crying,Sir
为什么愤怒
Why are you angry?
因为我摔倒了 长官
Because I fell over, Sir.
你可以走了
You may go.
遵命 长官
Sir
教我拳击吧
Teach me to box.
为什么
Why?
很多原因 最主要的是可以保护我自己
Lots of reasons. The main reason being to defend myself.
他们都看到你羞辱了我
They all saw you humiliate me.
他们不会归因于你太强
They will not put that down to you being good .
而是觉得我太差了
but to me being bad
他们会觉得我没什么好怕的
They’ll think they have nothing to fear from me
然后因此而攻击我
and they’ll attack.
你应该在你挑战我之前就想到这个
You should have thought of that before you challenged me.
我不得不挑战你
I had to challenge you.
一个人承受耻辱是有限度的
There is only so much contempt a man can take.
如果人们瞧不起你
If people have contempt for you,
那一定是有原因的
there must be a reason.
不
No.
我只是不能灵活地应对其他人
I duck and dive no more than any man.
我也和他们一样小心翼翼
I sniff around no more than any man.
我不比任何人差
I am no worse than any man here.
但是当人们处在这样一个地方
But when people are in a place like this,
他们需要有个人成为泄愤工具
they need someone to shit upon.
你想在这里找到什么
What did you expect to find here?
土著女人
Native women;
全裸的
all naked,
每个人的胸部都很大
all carrying armfuls of fruit,
都想和我做爱
all wanting to fuck me.
教我拳击吧
Teach me to box.
还有别的吗
Anything else?
有
Yes.
“我希望
"I hope”
“我希望"
“能亲手写我的下一封信”
“To be able to write my next letter myself."
柯林斯上尉在教我读书和写字
Captain Collins is teaching me to read and write.
每天大约就半小时左右
Only half an hour or so each day
所以可能要花很长时间才能学成 但是
so it will take a long time, but,
到时候即使我不需要你了
and even when I no longer need you,
其他人还是需要的
others will.
成百上千人还会继续需要你的帮忙
Hundreds will go on needing you.
对不起
I am sorry. .
如果这么说伤害到你了 我很抱歉
I am sorry if I have hurt you
“我希望
Er ... I hope ...
“能够”
to be able ...
我能帮忙吗
May I help?
伊丽莎白·奎恩
Elizabeth Quinn -
伊丽莎白·巴伦特怀孕了
Elizabeth Barrett is pregnant.
在英格兰 这可不是什么好消息
In England that would not be good news.
会是一桩丑闻
It would be a scandal..
为什么在这里不是呢
Why is it not a scandal here?
嗯
Hmm
因为 他们在这里结婚了
Well they are married here.
他们离家一万英里远呢
And they are ten thousand miles from home.
假设离家只有十英里 这会是丑闻吗
Yeah, if it were ten miles from home, would it be a scandal?
当然会
Of course.
那一百英里呢 一千英里呢
A hundred miles? A thousand miles?
多远才够我们改变道德标准呢
How far must we be for rules to change?
我一个人能处理得了 谢谢你
I think I can manage now, thank you.
我只是说说而已
I am only thinking aloud.
嗯 我知道
Yes, I realise that.
进来
Come in.
你想见 哦 你好 黛博拉
You wish to se - oh Hello, Deborah.
你好 教士
Hello Reverend.
你想见我吗
You wish to see me?
是的 是的 关于教堂的事
Yes, yes. It’s about the church.
我知道你想说什么
I know what you are about to say.
哦 是吗
You do?
是的 你想问“起好名字了吗”
Yes. Have I thought of a name?
答案是肯定的
And the answer is yes:
我们准备以你的名字来命名
we want to name it after you.
我并不是想说这个
That is not what I was about to say.
虽然我喜欢你的回答 没错 但是
It is very good of you, yes, but,
我希望你事先可以跟我讲一下
I wish you’d spoken to me about it first.
这是宗教的事
It is a spiritual matter.
我不需要跟你商量宗教方面的事 总督
I need not discuss spiritual matters, Governor
一起喝点朗姆酒吧
Will you join me in a tot of rum?
你有朗姆酒吗
You have rum?
是的
Yes
哦
Oh?
好的 我戒了一个月
Yes, I abstain for a month
现在可以放纵一个月了
so I can spoil myself the following month.
可以帮忙倒酒吗 黛博拉
Would you, Deborah?
当然
Of course.
要是喝酒不觉得是享受
Better not to drink at all
那还不如一点都不喝
than to drink and feel no benefit.
教士
Reverend,
我知道这很难
this is difficult
因为我知道这座教堂对你有多重要
because I know how much the church means to you.
但我觉得 不应该让罪犯来建它
But I do not think the convicts should be building it.
为什么呢
Why is that?
啊 谢谢
Ah thank you.
他们半饥不饱的 也不够强壮
They are half starved. They are not strong enough.
有人喝了我的酒
Someone has been at this.
是的
Yes
你知道是谁吗
Do you know who?
是我
Me
你吗
You?
是的
Yes
你又不喝酒
You do not drink.
我想试试
I thought I would try it.
为什么
Why?
我感到很紧张 很焦虑
I was feeling nervous and tense and I,
所以我想
I thought ...
我去把它换掉
I will replace it.
不不不 不用了 这样挺好
No, no, no, no, no. It is fine.
来两个小杯
Two small ones then.
不用给我倒 你自己留着喝吧
No save it for yourself.
不 就两小杯
No. Two, two small ones.
我刚刚说到哪了
Now where was I?
你说那些人不够强壮
You were saying that the men were not strong enough.
没错
Yes.
吃多少东西得干多少活
What you take in must equal what you put out.
要是吃多了 你就会长胖
If it is more, you go fat.
吃少了 就会饿死
If it is less, you die.
除了有肢体力量
There is physical strength
还有精神力量
and there is spiritual strength.
按这样说 男人们在建教堂的时候
In this case the men are building a church
他们的精神力量会支撑他们
so their spiritual strength will sustain them.
只有单纯的体力 教士
There is just strength, Reverend.
晚安
Good night.
你要走了吗
Are you going?
是的
Yes
这么早吗
So early?
是的
Yes.
晚安 教士
Good night, Reverend.
晚安 黛博拉
Good night, Deborah.
你不舒服吗
Are you not well?
没有 我很好 晚安
No, I am fine. Good night.
对不起 我们说到哪了
I am sorry: Where was I again?
“只有单纯的体力”
"There is just strength".
是的 是的 他们所拥有的力量
Yes, yes. And what strength they have
要用来开辟土地
is needed for clearing the land,building
以及建造一些我们赖以生存的建筑
- things on which their very survival hangs
所以很抱歉 我不能让他们干别的
and I am sorry I cannot allow them to do anything else.
我和我妻子会自己解决的
Then my wife and I will do it ourselves.
两个人根本不够
That is beyond any couple.
我要让你看看什么是精神力量
I would like to show you what spiritual strength
所能做到的 总督
can achieve, Governor.
我不会跟他说话的
I will not speak to him.
上次他非要我说话 但这次我不会了
He made me speak last time but this time I will not.
他可以得到我的身体 的确
He can have my body, yes:
我没办法反抗
there is nothing I can do about that.
但是他永远也得不到我的灵魂
But he will not have my mind.
也得不到我的心
Or my heart.
我会从这里走过去
I will go on from here.
凯瑟琳·麦克维蒂找您 长官
Katherine Mcvitie for you, Sir.
他确实是个勇敢的男人
He is ten times the man that ...
但更多的时候是个士兵
... he is. And twenty times the soldier.
你说勋爵走进了房间
His Lordship walked into the room, you said,
然后把你按在床上
threw you onto the bed
要不是他妻子恰好在场
and would have raped you
他差点就强暴了你
but for his wife happening on the scene.
我问了柯林斯上尉
I put that to Captain Collins
因为他有你所有的档案
because he has files on you all and erm,
他说你在撒谎
he said it is lies.
你是楼下的女仆
You were the downstairs maid.
去楼上干什么呢
What were you doing upstairs?
是去勾引他吧
You enticed him.
你准备等他睡着了 就去偷他的钱夹
You planned to wait until he slept and walk off with his wallet.
对此你有什么想说的吗
What have you to say to that?
不说话吗
Not talking?
是不是因为你没法为自己辩解
Now is that because you have no defence,
也没有理由开脱了吧
nothing to offer in mitigation?
或者说这是你的某种策略呢
Or is, is it a tactic of some sort?
嗯
Hmm?
我是个士兵
I am a soldier.
我喜欢一丝不挂又话少的女人
Naked and dumb is exactly how I like my women
如果你想要故意引我不高兴
so if this is meant to disconcert me,
我向你保证 不会的
I can assure you it does not.
所以
So,
告诉我
please: Tell. Me.
为什么你不说话
Why. You are not. Speaking.
今晩想吃什么
What food would you like tonight?
我有些风干的豌豆
I er, have some dried peas.
想来一点吗
Would you like some?
他不爱你
He does not love you.
他对你有欲望 没错
He might lust after you, yes,
但那仅仅是生理需求
but that is all: lust.
把你分享出去他是不会受伤的
Sharing you cannot possibly hurt him
因为你就是个妓女
for you are a whore
男人们总是一起分享妓女
and men always share a whore.
这样做太蠢了 凯瑟琳
This is rather silly, Katherine,
因为我知道你有多想赶快结束这一切
because I know how much you like to get it over with
然后回到他身边
and get back to him and,
但很遗憾 你不说话我是不会开始的
sadly, I will not start until you have spoken.
我们可以这样待到明天早上
We could be here till morning.
你想让我说什么
What would you like me to say?
一些实话
Something truthful.
你觉得我讨厌你
You think I hate you
你是对的
and you are right.
我确实讨厌你
I do.
但你认为我只是鄙视你
But you think I have nothing but contempt for you
那你就错了
and you are wrong.
因为偶尔
Because occasionally, .
也只是偶尔
just occasionally,
我会同情你
I feel sorry for you
我想我要开始了
I think I will begin now.
你是真的在问
Are you seriously asking
为什么一个人要学会读书写字吧
why a man should be able to read and write?
是 是的
Yes, yes.
你给伊丽莎白写了封信 对吧
You left a letter for Elizabeth - am I right?
一封信吗
A letter?
开玩笑
Clown!
那时我以为他们要绞死我了
When I thought they were hanging me, yeah. Thanks for that.
是的 谢谢你做的那些
Thanks for that.
你肯定是让莱特斯·莫洛伊帮你写的
But you had to get Letters Molloy to write it for you.
写了什么
What did it say?
没什么
Nothing.
你要把那张王拿起来吗
Are you, are you picking that king up?
如此珍贵的一封信
Is it right
让别人知道了内容 这样好吗
for another man to know the contents of such a precious letter?
莱特斯·莫洛伊
Letters Molloy
是我们当中最值得信任的人
is one of the most trustworthy men amongst us.
不过
Nevertheless ...
这张王 你是要还是不要
Are you picking that king up not?
我故意的
I am deliberating.
你写了什么
What did it say?
我写的是“等我死了再看”
It said, "To be read in the event of my death" and,
但如你所见 我还活着
as you can see I am still alive.
你有那张该死的王吗
Are you having that bloody king?
是的 我有
Yes I am!!
因为我知道你想要它
Because I know you wanted it.
太感谢了
Thank you very much.
我赢了
I am out.
快看呀
Look at that.
莱特斯·莫洛伊先生要见你 长官
It’s Letters Molloy, Sir.
进来
Come in.
我读完了
I have finished it.
啊 你喜欢吗
Oh? Did you enjoy it?
是的 很喜欢
Yes. Very much.
你要再拿一本吗
Would you like another?
如果不是很麻烦的话
If it is not too much trouble.
不 一点也不麻烦
No, not at all.
呃
Er ...
1762年度世界大事年鉴
The Annual Register of 1762.
啊 好 谢谢
Oh? Yes? Thank you.
还有事吗
Is there something else?
你在教斯塔宾识字
You are teaching Stubbins to read?
是的 斯塔宾和其他一些人
Stubbins and a few others, yes.
没必要
Well there’s, there’s no need.
我很乐意帮他们写信 是的
I am more than happy to go on doing it for them. Yes -
他们很感激你为他们所做的一切
They are very grateful for all that you do,
莱特斯
Letters,
但他们迟早要自己做这些事
but they would sooner do it for themselves.
怎么了
What is wrong?
柯林斯上尉
Captain Collins,
如果斯塔宾学会了读信 他会自杀的
if Stubbins learns to read, he will kill himself.
为什么会那样呢
How can that be?
他不是一直随身带着他妻子的一封信吗
He carries around a letter from his wife. Yes?
是的
Yes
你看过那封信吗
Have you ever read it?
没有
No
他收到这封信时在泰晤士河上的监狱船里
He got it on the prison ship in the Thames.
就在我们出发前两天
Two days before we sailed.
他让我念给他听
He asked me to read it to him.
在她写着
Where she had written,
“我遇到了另一个男人”
"I have met another man,"
我却念成了
I read,
“我将永远对你忠贞不渝 亲爱的”
"I will always be true to you, my darling."
什么
What!
他要去世界的另一边去了 你知道的
He was sailing to the other side of the world,
而且几乎可以肯定永远也见不到她了
you see and almost certain never to see her again.
所以 为什么要打破他的美梦呢
So why crush him?
你知道我的困境了吧
You see my dilemma.
恐怕你现在也让我为难了
I'm afraid you have now made it mine as well.
对不起
I am sorry.
我会拥有一个跟你一样美丽的女人
I would have a woman just as beautiful as you,
但是比你贞洁
but decent too.
受过良好教育 有教养
Educated. Refined.
这是在这个地方 才让我们在一起
It is only this place that has brought us together
但是 你却这样对我
and yet you treat me like this.
我可以走了吗 求你了
May I go please
不行
不 以后每周我都要你来三个晚上
No. No, I will have you three nights a week in future.
我会跟麦克唐纳下士进行必要的协商
I will make the necessary arrangements with Corporal Macdonald.
你的豌豆在那里
Your peas are there.
你不想要了吗
You do not want them?
你可以走了
You may go.
打扫房间的女仆那天请假了
The chambermaid was off that day.
她去堕胎了
She was getting an abortion,
勋爵帮她安排的
arranged by his Lordship.
我当时在替她的班
I was doing her job.
再见
Goodbye.
他让我以后每周过去三个晚上
He wants me three nights a week.
那你说了什么
And what did you say?
我能说什么
What could I say?
凯瑟琳
Katherine!
没事了
It’s alright,
别怕
come on.
麦克唐纳下士
Corporal Macdonald.
长官
Sir.
她是游过来的吗
She swam to here?
是的 长官
Yes, Sir.
离岸100码吗
A hundred yards from shore?
是的 长官
Yes, Sir.
在晚上吗
In the dark.
是的 长官
Yes, Sir.
她想投海自尽
She was trying to drown herself.
不是的 长官
No, Sir.
她怎么敢
How dare she!
她怎么敢这么做
对不起
I am sorry. .
他们马上就会把尸体运过来
They are bringing in his body
你是怎么知道的
How do you know?
我昨晚游过去的时候撞上了他
I swam into it last night.
游到那么远吗
So far out?
我当时想自杀
I was trying to kill myself.
是的 但很不幸 我没成功
Yes. But sadly I did not succeed.
我看到了马斯顿 他的样子很恐怖
I saw Marston and he looked horrible
我不想变成跟他一样可怕
and I did not want to look like that.
他活着的时候看起来也一样可怕
He looked like that alive.
真的很对不起
I am so sorry.
詹姆斯
James!
听着 你要么拼死反抗 要么就逃走
Listen, you stay and fight your corner or you run.
如果他选择逃走 就需要淡水
If it is "run" he will need fresh water.
我去拿一些
I will get some.
他差点把你饿死了
He was starving you to death
他们却没给你任何帮助
and they did not lift a finger to help you
你还能怎样呢
so what else could you do?
这么说没用 汤米
It will not work, Tommy.
他已经向所有人宣布了
He has announced to everyone
一旦找到了尸体 他就会绞死我
he will hang me once the body is found
他不会食言的 我完了
and he will not go back on that. I am finished.
所以我必须逃走
So I must run.
快跑
Go
去哪里呢
To where?
丛林
The bush.
你在丛林里是无法生存的
You will not survive in the bush.
我去找杰弗森
I will find Jefferson.
杰弗森已经死了
Jefferson is dead.
哦 是吗 那我去找土著
Yeah, well I will find the natives,
求得他们的怜悯
I throw myself upon their mercy.
他们不会帮你的
They will not help you.
我知道
I know.
但浪费一顿美餐是可耻的
But it is a shame to waste a good meal.
但愿能再见
Till we meet again.
我在那个地狱般的船舱里被关了六个月
I was cooped up in that hell-hole of a ship for six months,
然后被扔到这个地方受苦 挨饿
tossed up here to burn and starve, work
拼死干活
until I drop.
但是你知道吗 伊丽莎白
And do you know what, Elizabeth?
我愿意把这个过程再经历一遍
I would do it all again
因为这样
because by doing it
我会遇到你
I met you.
弗里曼在哪里
Where’s Freeman?
快把那个人铐住
Chain that man!
快点
Go!
向他开枪
Shoot that man.
快点
Go
趴下
Down!
开火
Fire!
抓住他
After him!
快点 跑步前进
Come on!  On the double!
要是看到他 就开火
D’you see him?  Fire at will.
大家尽量待在一起
Stick together.
你们两个 搜下面
You two, search down there!
是 长官
Yes sir
全能的上帝
Amighty God
哦 不
Oh No
抓住他
Take him!